VUSUMUSI MKHABELA

"A highly motivated **BSc. IT final year student** passionate in emerging technology innovations as well as in data engineering, data analysis and various data security strategies in businesses."



CONTACT



(+27) 76 753 1710



veemkhabela1996@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/vusimkh/



Vanderbilpark, Gauteng

EDUCATION

GRADE 12/ MATRIC

Westridge High School, Cape Town

Mathematics, Computer
 Application Technology, Life
 Science
 2010 - 2014

BSC. INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

North-West University, Vaal Campus, Gauteng 2021

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

- Programming: C#, Java,
 JavaScript[novice], PHP, MySQL,
 ASP.NET, Python, Oracle, NoSQL
- Web: HTML5, CSS3, jQuery

SUMMARY

I am a principled and an enthusiastic individual who has a considerable interest in data analytics, innovative web developments, in advancing cyber security strategies and next generation technologies. I employ excellent agility, leadership, team-player skills, and multi-tasking strengths acquired directly from my experiences such as with clients, students, and respectfully liaise with the upper structures. While my short retail experience has equipped me with strong analysis skills, general marketing skills, and relationship building, I have demonstrated an ability to continuously learn, adapt, share, or apply and advance that knowledge. I value honesty, integrity, and accountability.

EXPERIENCE

Sales Assistant — Makro (Agent: Hospitality Express)

APRIL 2015 - NOV 2015

Working for this agency at Makro Montague Gardens, I was responsible for assisting with in-store sales from the electronics department and interacting with customers on the daily. This included answering questions regarding products or services at Makro and supervising and promoting new restocking of products.

- Serving customers and dealing with enquiries.
- Managing product inventories at the store.
- Conduct effective sales.

Residence Chairperson and Public Relations Officer —

North-West University (Student Affairs Department)

SEP 2016 - SEP 2017

As an executive student officer in the residence, I was responsible for the management of the students in terms of the rules for students the general University Council policy and sections of the residence's constitution.

 Acting as chief spokesperson and representative of the residence.

VUSUMUSI MKHABELA

"A highly motivated **BSc. IT final year student** passionate in emerging technology innovations as well as in data engineering, data analysis and various data security solutions in businesses."

SKILLS continued

PROFFESIONAL

- Leader and Team player
- Business Agility and Analysis
- Customer Services
- Analytic thinking
- Verbal & Written
 Communication

ACHIEVEMENTS

PREFECT

Westridge High School 2014

TOP 2 ACADEMIC ACHIEVER

Westridge High School 2014

LANGUAGES

English, IsiXhosa, IsiZulu,
 Sesotho, Afrikaans (mod)

EXPERIENCE continued

- Provide leadership and monitor and control housecommittee activities and delegate duties where necessary.
- Ensure the University's Risk Management policy is applied.

Supplementary Instructor (SI) Leader— North-West University (Academic Development and Support Department)

JAN - JUNF 2017

As a supplementary instructor leader, I had to facilitate first year IT student learning and help students understand analytic mathematical concepts and applications better.

- Plan and conduct two 60-minute SI sessions per week throughout the semester.
- Plan and meet with the mathematics professor periodically for reporting and timesheet submission.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Practical approach to Web Designing, HTML5 & CSS3 — MasterGrade IT, Cape Town

MARCH 2015

REFERENCES

Ms. Prem Coopoo

Dean of Student Affairs, Cape Peninsula University of Tech 083 645 7466, coopooprem@cput.ac.za

Ms. Antionette De Lange

Hospitality Express (Makro Agent) 021 552 7699, antionette@hxp.co.za

Mr. Akhona Dalasile

North-West University VTC Residence Officer & House Parent 079 068 8813, 21972109@nwu.ac.za

Mr. Adrian Cupido

Makro Sales Manager (2015) 021 550 6474, adrian.cupido@makro.co.za

Ms. Leeandri Van Dyk

Senior Account Manager & Career Development Professional (2014) MasterGrade IT 021 419 3213, leandri@nhct.co.za